Nahual is a horror film directed by Ricardo Islas.
Katia Montero's exotic getaway spirals into terror when she
becomes possessed by a bloodthirsty animal spirit.
Erotic encounters, violence, and ancient legends converge to
deliver a chilling new twist on a South American myth.
Katia Montero, played by Jenny Sanchez.
Fabian Gutierrez, played by Diego Herrera.
Yanay, played by Miriam Román.
Farmer, played by Kristy V Acosta.
I Am Frankelda (Spanish: Soy Frankelda) is a 2025 Mexican stop motion animated
musical dark fantasy film written and directed by Arturo and Roy Ambriz.
It is a prequel to the television series Frankelda's Book of Spooks, becoming the first Mexican film made
entirely in stop-motion technique, and features the voices of Mireya Mendoza, Arturo Mercado Jr.
and Luis Leonardo Suárez.
The plot follows Francisca Imelda, a young aspiring writer in the mid 19th century Mexico and her struggles to
fullfil her dreams after being approached by a prince who needs her help to save his kingdom.
I Am Frankelda had its world premiere as the opening film of the 40th Guadalajara International Film Festival on
June 6, 2025, as well as competing in the Best International Animation Feature Film category.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.